A Guide to the T. W. Hatcher Collection, 1919-1970 (Bulk 1920-1930)
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
T. W. Hatcher Collection 1919-1970 (Bulk 1920-1930)
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University, Blacksburg, Va.
Ms1987-040
2 boxes; 0.6. cu. ft.
The collection contains notes from Hatcher's tenure as a student at VPI, as well as VPI ephemera from the 1950s. The collecton contains photographs from campus and other locations, taken in the 1920s. Later materials consist of reports from the National Bank of Blacksburg.
T. W. Hatcher
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
The T. W. Hatcher Collection was donated to Special Collections in 1987.
Biographical Information
T. (Thomas) W. (Watkins) Hatcher was a student at VPI from 1919 to 1922, graduating with a defree in Mechanical Engineering. In 1924, Hatcher joined the Math Department as an Instructor, and became an Assistant Professor in 1926. He received a PhD in Mathematics from Cornell University in 1931. In 1943, he was named Acting Head of the department at VPI, a position that became permanent the following year. He served as Head of the Math Department until 1963. Hatcher retired in 1964, and began contributing to a scholarship that has continued in his name ever since. He was also on the Board of the National Bank of Blacksburg. Hatcher died in 1979.
Scope and Content
The collection contains class notes from Hatcher's tenure as a student at VPI, as well as VPI ephemera from the 1950s. The collection contains photographs from campus and other locations, taken in the 1920s. Later materials consist of reports written about the National Bank of Blacksburg.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged by type of material.
Contents List
- VPI Directory of Living Alumni, 1970. (Box-folder 1:1)
- National Bank of Blacksburg Annual Reports, 1955-1956, 1964. (Box-folder 1:2)
- National Bank of Blacksburg Reports, 1959-1960, 1963-1965. (Box-folder 1:3)
- VPI ephemera, 1920s, 1950s. (Box-folder 1:4)
- Photograph album, VPI and ROTC, 1920s. (Box-folder 1:5)
- Photographs, 1919, n.d. (Box-folder 1:6)
- Notes, n.d. (Box-folder 2:1)
- Bound Notes, Advanced Calculus, 1928-1929. (Box-folder 2:2)
- Thesis [Notes?], n.d. (Box-folder 2:3)
- Bound Notes, 1929-1930. (Box-folder 2:4)
- Notes, Modern Operational Mathematics in Engineering, 1947(?). (Box-folder 2:5)
- Salary List, 1923-1924. (Box-folder 2:6)